Ah, Aryaryagi-san.
It's Araragi.
Sorry, I stuttered.
Don't say people's names like Careless Hachibei does.
I think that it's cuter like that.
Don't you think it suits you surprisingly well?
Anyway, Araragi-san, where are you going?
I'm going home.
Are you going out after that?
Yeah, to Senjougahara's place.
Our midterms are coming up soon.
That's why we agreed to meet up so she can tutor me.
Hey... you still remember Senjougahara, don't you?
Oh, that tsundere.
But as I recall...
you and Senjougahara-san are in a boy-girl relationship, aren't you?
I guess you could say that.
So, even though you say she'll be tutoring you,
won't you just end up flirting with each other?
Just before the test that decides if you can repeat a grade or not
you're actually just going to your lover's place.
I personally feel that's suicidal, Araragi-san.
What I'm facing is whether I can graduate or not.
Also, don't say it's suicidal!
But I feel that it is indeed suicidal.
It seems like I'll have to bring this issue to light and put an end to it sooner or later.
That which protrudes should protrude?
Are you referring to my breasts or my butt?
Araragi-san, what are you looking for in an elementary school student's body?
Shut up.
Don't try to rub non-existent mistakes in people's faces!
Hey, Hachikuji, you...
Hey, Araragi-senpai.
What a coincidence.
This is way too well arranged to be a coincidence!
Hachikuji, that girl, she escaped.
What's been wrong with you lately?
"This is way too well arranged to be a coincidence", huh?
It seems obvious, but really is hard to think of.
It was the perfect comment for the situation.
This is really what you call "witty", isn't it!
Yeah, that's right.
Actually, I was chasing after you.
I figured you were.
I see! You knew!
As expected of Araragi-senpai.
You completely saw through the actions of a novice like me, right?
I feel so shy and embarrassed.
But, I'm still sincere in my utmost respect towards you.
Don't you have club activities after school?
Can you really hang around in a place like this?
Yeah, it's okay because I hurt my hand.
Kanbaru, what do you want from me today?
Ah, right.
Have you read the world section of today's morning paper?
I'd like to hear your opinion...
regarding Russia's current political situation.
What is this, a current affairs joke?!
Or are you more interested in India's IT industry?
I didn't read the news this morning.
I see.
Anyway, Araragi-senpai,
did you encounter anything weird today?
Huh? No.
It's been normal.
I feel like the approaching placement tests are really giving me a headache, though.
Later on I'm going to a study group, as well.
Study group?
But, even though it's supposedly a study group...
It's only me, one on one, receiving help.
It's really more like me being tutored.
You see, there's someone in my class that has amazing grades...
I'm kinda asking them a favor.
It's Senjougahara-senpai, isn't it?
You know her?
If you're talking about a person with good grades in your class,
it has to be Senjougahara-senpai, right?
There have been rumors about her for a while.
Yeah, I guess...
Anyway, I guess I should go then!
I think I'll just leave for today.
I see.
Araragi-senpai, good luck.
Rararagi-san.
Hachikuji, don't sing out my name so musically.
My name is Araragi.
Sorry. I stuttered.
No, it was on purpose.
I st-stuttered!
IT WASN'T ON PURPOSE?!
Speaking of which, who's that person?
The ace of basketball; my underclassman.
I don't really get it, but...
about three days ago she started blatantly following me around everywhere.
Honestly, I have no clue what she wants.
Could it be that she likes you?
Impossible.
I'm not the protagonist of some gal game.
How could I suddenly become so popular?
My womanly instincts are telling me I'm right.
She may confess to you in a few days.
What will you do? What will you do?
You know, I don't really like when people try to explain everything with love.
There's just no way.
But anyway, I've...
already cleared the hardest character.
I feel like someone has said something bad about me.
In any case, teaching a person to study really is difficult.
Why am I studying?
Isn't it because you're stupid?
I haven't worried about my studies once in my life,
so I don't understand what you don't understand.
Are you kidding...?
If I help you prepare for this placement test,
well, at least passing won't be a problem.
But what exactly are you thinking of doing from now on?
From now on?
Your future.
My future?
Even if you ask me about my future...
It's already the end of May in your third year of high school, you know.
You said something like being fine with just graduating,
but does that mean you're going to look for a job after graduation?
Umm...
Or does it mean that you're going to live on part time jobs?
Or become a NEET?
Well, I suppose you could go to a technical school to raise your qualifications first, too.
What are you, my mom?
Mom? What are you talking about?
I'm your lover, aren't I?
My future?
Yeah, I guess you're right. I really should decide on it soon.
Senjougahara, what are you going to do?
Go on to university.
I can probably get direct admission.
I see.
But if possible, I'd really like to follow the same path as you.
Well, with my grades that's a bit...
Then what should we do?
Maybe live together after graduation?
If we do that, even if our futures are different,
we'd probably have even more time together than we do now.
Well, that wouldn't be bad, I guess...
It wouldn't be bad? What do you mean by that?
That's a great idea. Let's definitely do that.
Oh, I see.
What exactly is "dating?"
You're sighing quite a bit, aren't you, Araragi-kun?
Have you heard that every time you sigh, you lose a piece of happiness?
Then I'd say I've let thousands of pieces of happiness go already.
I don't really care however much happiness you let go,
but I'd really appreciate it if you didn't sigh in front of me.
Because it's annoying.
You really say some harsh things.
Even though I say it's annoying,
I'm really just lovesick.
When you say it like that, you make it really hard to react, you know.
Speaking of which, did you know, Araragi-kun?
I... have never broken up with a guy before.
So I don't intend to break up with you, either.
So that basically means that neither of us know how to appeal to the other...?
Hey, Senjougahara.
What?
Do you still carry things like staplers around?
Now that you mention it, I guess I haven't been, recently.
How careless.
Careless, huh?
You were the ace of track and field during middle school, weren't you?
Yeah.
Are you going to do track anymore?
No. I don't have any reason to.
I have no intention of going back to how I was then.
Ah, right.
Hey, Senjougahara.
What?
Do you know Kanbaru Suruga?
Kanbaru Suruga? Yeah.
What a nostalgic name.
Oh, I see..
So they really were friends?
When I mentioned the study group,
Kanbaru didn't think of Hanekawa, the top in the class, first,
but thought of Senjougahara instead.
Could that be the reason?
Yeah, she was my underclassman during middle school.
Isn't she still? We're in the same school-
Kanbaru?
You say it rather affectionately, don't you.
But what about her, Araragi-kun?
If I remember correctly, you recover from injuries rather quickly, don't you?
A mere eyeball shouldn't be a problem then, right?
Stop it! Stop it!
Even if it's me, eyes are bad!
I haven't done anything to feel guilty about, and I don't think of her affectionately, either!
You're my one and only!
Oh, is that so? You say rather nice things, don't you?
I suppose I might have gotten too worked up just now.
Did I frighten you, Araragi-kun?
One of these days, you are going to kill someone. I know it.
Well when that time comes, I suppose I'll pick you, then.
I'll pick you as my first opponent.
I won't pick anybody but you. I promise.
I don't want such a warped romance!
There's nothing wrong with it. Just accept it.
Basically, me killing you
means that the one closest to you when you die will be me.
Isn't it romantic?
No. I'd rather anyone kill me but you!
No matter who I'm killed by or how I'm killed,
I feel like it would be way better than being killed by you!
What are you talking about? I don't want that.
If you are killed by someone other than me,
I will kill whoever did it and screw the promise.
Anyway, we were talking about Kanbaru, weren't we?
Because I was the track and field ace and she was the basketball ace,
even though we were in different grades, we still had some interaction.
Plus...
Plus?
Even outside of club activities, in my private life,
I also imposed on her, or perhaps was made to look after her, many times.
Anyway, Araragi-kun.
Before we get into that, why did you mention her now?
Care to tell?
If there's nothing to hide,
you should be able to explain this to me properly.
Y-Yeah...
I see.
Hey, Araragi-kun.
What?
Above is water, below is great fire.
That's... the furnace that heats the bath, right?
Wrong! The answer is...
Kanbaru Suruga's house.
What are you planning to do to the house of the school star?!
Forget it. Anyway, jokes aside...
Araragi-kun, Kanbaru discovered my secret one year earlier than you.
Really?
It was when I had just become a junior in high school.
Basically, right after Kanbaru started at Naoetsu High School.
Judging from her personality, she...
probably offered to help you, am I right?
Yes, that's exactly right.
But I declined her offer.
I used the same method that I used against you.
Despite that you still tried to help me.
But Kanbaru has never come close to me after that.
That's about the extent of our relationship.
But you were friends, right?
Yeah, during middle school, we were. Now is different.
She's just a complete stranger.
Even though I get your relationship now,
why is she following me around?
She must have heard that we started going out.
What?
In other words, she's curious about what kind of guy you started dating, and came to find out about me?
It's probably something like that, I think.
Sorry for the trouble, Araragi-kun.
Really, I guess I don't have any explanation for it.
You could say that it's my fault for managing my interpersonal relationships improperly.
But she was pushed away pretty ruthlessly by you a year ago, right?
So from then on she had nothing to do with you, right?
Would she really care about something like you getting a boyfriend?
It may sound strange coming from me,
but to Kanbaru, I was once her idolized senpai.
So when I pushed her away, I tried to take extra caution so as not to leave any future problems.
But it appears that she still hasn't forgotten about me.
Don't call her annoying.
She doesn't have any ill intentions, right?
Besides-
She is annoying.
This has nothing to do with having ill intentions or not.
Hi. Sorry for the wait. Hanekawa speaking.
What's up?
It's really rare for you to call me.
Oh, it's all right.
I'm just doing some light studying.
Yeah, that's right.
Yeah, of course I know that.
Oh, really?
The Valhalla Combination.
They used to be known as the Valhalla Combination.
Senjougahara-san from track and field and Kanbaru-san from basketball.
The Valhalla Combination.
The Baruhara Combination?
What does "Baruhara" mean?
The "baru" is from Kanbaru and the "hara" is from Senjougahara.
That's why it's "Baruhara."
But it also means Valhalla, which in Norse Mythology is the hall in which the highest god, Odin, resides.
It's the sacred hall of the god of war, where the heroes who fell in battle would be welcomed.
It's the "kami" from Kanbaru and the "senjou" from Senjougahara.
That's why it's the "Valhalla Combination."
Wow, there's really someone around who thinks of names like that?
Well, since they were called a combination,
they probably weren't on bad terms and didn't have too many problems, don't you think?
I see.
Senjougahara-san kept participating in her club right up to graduation,
and since both of them were in sports clubs, they must have socialized, even if only a little bit.
You really know everything, don't you?
I don't know everything. I just know what I know.
That's right. She was popular with both the boys and girls.
Her reputation was very good with both her seniors and classmates.
But really, she was probably most popular with the junior girls.
That's what you really wanted to ask, isn't it?
But it shouldn't matter to you what Senjougahara-san was like in the past.
You like the current Senjougahara-san, don't you?
Liking her is good, but make sure you keep a clean and proper boy-girl relationship, okay, Araragi-kun?
Senjougahara-san seems really serious,
so I don't think it'll turn into a bad relationship.
She's very complicated, you know.
I don't mean to sound like I think I know her very well...
but she's created an impenetrable self-field.
You have one, too.
Everyone has the self-field known as privacy,
but both you and Senjougahara-san lock yourselves inside like you're being besieged.
People like that tend to find socializing with others depressing.
You should know what I'm talking about.
Both of you.
But, Araragi-kun...
Hating socializing with people is different than hating people.
I'm bothereed by the very fact that people exist, but you're an exception.
You get what I mean, right?
And...
what I want to say, right?
It's nothing weird.
It's completely normal to want to know more about your girlfriend.
But I think it's best not to dive too deep into your lover's past.
Don't let it become half interest and half amusement.
Araragi-kun, make sure you act in moderation in that regard.
Anyway, bye-bye.
If I can, I'd like to bring back what she has lost, what she threw away.
My way of thinking might be meddling in other people's business,
and it could even be said to be bothersome to them.
But I can't stop thinking about it.
It's just not possible for me to stop.
Could you deliver this to Oshino-san for me?
What is it?
Oh, it's Oshino-san's payment.
I didn't think you would prepare it this fast.
Did you work part-time?
I helped somewhat with my father's job.
Well, to be precise, I should say I forced him to let me help.
That's how I got the money.
She trusted me with it, and I forgot it at her house.
Araragi-kun.
Yo, it's been a while.
You forgot this.
This isn't Karen!
And I'm not Tsukihi!
Well then, who is it?
Daegi Galbi isn't digital.
Roadside stones aren't robots.
The top ranking is not the king.
An overhaul isn't a hole.
A schedule isn't a joule!
Elocution isn't erotic.
An undeserved honor isn't the same as a small honor at all, is it?
Getting favor isn't the same as getting super lovey!
It really isn't?
Really, it's not.
Preview quiz!
Quiz!
Not!
No?
Next time, Suruga Monkey Part 2.
So if it's not a quiz, what is it?
It's a quiz...